Charles Tomlinson Griffes Collection, 1768-2006, undated
Elmira College
- SERIES 4: MATERIALS ABOUT GRIFFES [1903-2006, undated], SERIES NOTE: This series contains materials that were published posthumously and contribute to the understanding of the legacy of Griffes as a composer. Most of the materials are from festivals hosted by Elmira College and SUNY Cortland, with other biographical materials published by Schirmer, Griffes’ sheet music publisher. The collection contains programs, newspaper clippings from local papers and scrapbooks that document the life and times of Charles Tomlinson Griffes. This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Miscellaneous -- Poster for 1982 concert and exhibit at SUNY Cortland with photograph from exhibit, photocopy of newspaper article about Mary Broughton's trip to Europe, 1903, 1903 - 1982 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Scrapbook: "Postmarten Album" -- contains newspaper clippings, recital programs, articles, obituaries, 1911 - 1923 (Box 5)
  - *Scrapbook -- contains newsclippings of articles about Griffes and programs containing performances of his pieces, 1920 - 1925 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - "Charles Tomlinson Griffes" by John Tasker Howard -- Booklet from Schirmer's Course in Contemporary Musical biography, 1923 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Concert Programs -- Seven programs, 1923 - 1984 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - "Charles Griffes Memory is Revived by Tribute Paid Elmiran by Critic, June, 1931" -- Transcript of article, 4 p., 1903-2006 (4: 5)
  - Lawrence Gilman speech on Griffes -- Transcription, 4 p., March 9, 1936 (4: 6)
  - Charles Tomlinson Griffes at Elmira College -- Booklet, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Charles Tomlinson Griffes Festival materials (1) -- Tickets for 1964 concert, brochures, programs, and booklet "Charles Tomlinson Griffes at Elmira College," poster in OS1:1 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Charles Tomlinson Griffes Festival materials (2) -- Newspaper clippings from the event, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Postcard -- "Area Composer's Medley," by Talitha Botsford, depiction of several composer's homes in the upstate New York vicinity with a note from the artist, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - *Quarterly Journal, January, 1964 -- "Music," by Irving Lowens, with references to Griffes on p. 24 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - *Quarterly Journal, April, 1964 -- "A Second Holograph of Griffes' The Pleasure-Dome of Kubla Khan," by Irving Lowens (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1964 - 2006 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Chemung Historical Journal, March 1965 -- Includes Griffes article by Frederick C. St. Aubyn (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Dr. Wisbey -- Correspondence concerning Griffes exhibit, 1977; and, correspondence concerning Bicentennial Plaque for Griffes, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Charles T. Griffes Music Festival (Cortland, NY) -- Newspaper article and brochure, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Elmira Symphony and Choral Society -- Program and notes, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - NBC Symphony Orchestra, Sat., Nov. 20th -- Transcription of introduction of a performance of The Pleasure Dome of Kubla Khan, conducted by Pierre Monteaux, 1903-2006 (Box-folder 4: 18)
- SERIES 5: SOUND RECORDINGS [1976-2003, undated], SERIES NOTE: This series contains one recording by Griffes, the rest are interpretations. The Griffes recording is on a piano roll and cannot be played back in the Archive. The series has been arranged alphabetically and chronologically by material type.
  - Compact Disc: "Charles Tomlinson Griffes: Complete Piano Works, Vol. 1," Naxos, recorded 1995, 1999 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Compact Disc: "Charles Tomlinson Griffes: Complete Piano Works, Vol. 2," recorded 1999, 2000 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Compact Disc: Works by Charles Tomlinson Griffes, Boston Symphony Orchestra, Seiji Ozawa, Conductor, New World Records, recorded 1976, 2000 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Compact Disc: "Charles Griffes: Orchestral Music, Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, JoAnna Falletta, Conductor, Naxos, recorded 2002, 2003 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Music Roll: The White Peacock, "Roman Sketches op. 7, no. 1," played by Charles Griffes, 1976-2003 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Phonograph record: "Charles Tomlinson Griffes: Three Poems of Fiona MacLeod, The Pleasure-Dome of Kubla Khan, Song of the Dagger, Four German Songs, Four Impressions, Three Tone-Pictures, Boston Symphony Orchestra, Seiji Ozawa, Conductor, New World Records, 1976 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Phonograph record: "Charles Tomlinson Griffes: Piano Music," Aldo Mancinelli, Piano, Musical Heritage Society, 1977 (Box-folder 6: 7)